Guide to the Eugenia Flatow Papers 1940-2011 (bulk 1963-2005) MS 3175
New-York Historical Society
- Series I. Model Cities, 1958-1984 (bulk 1963-1973)
  - Subseries I.E. Subject Files, 1958-1984 (bulk 1965-1973)
    - HRA and Comm Corps (2 Folders), 1967-1969 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 16-17)
      Materials related to the Human Resources Administration (HRA) Model Cities Program, which sought to provide technical assistance with social planning and evaluate the effectiveness of publicly supported social services. Documents include correspondence, memorandums, Model Cities Notebooks, and "Draft: Proposal for a Training and Technical Assistance Program in the New York City Model Cities Areas."
    - HUD, 1968-1971 (Offsite-box 12, Folder 1)
    - In-Rem, 1968 (Offsite-box 12, Folder 2)
    - Letters In (2 Folders), 1967-1969 (Offsite-box 12, Folder 3-4)
    - Letters Out, 1967-1969 (Offsite-box 12, Folder 5)
    - Lindsay Housing Policy, 1963-1966 (Offsite-box 12, Folder 6)
    - Lindsay Papers (2 Folders), 1964-1970, bulk 1965 (Offsite-box 12, Folder 7-8)
    - Literature -- History and Policy Statements (3 Folders), 1966-1969 (Offsite-box 12, Folder 9-11)
    - Low-Income Housing, 1966-1967 (Offsite-box 12, Folder 12)
    - Maintenance Programs, 1968-1971 (Offsite-box 12, Folder 13)
    - MANN, 1969 (Offsite-box 12, Folder 14)
      Documents include: "Preliminary Report on Facets of the Model City Agency Organization and Related Governmental Agency Coordination Matters," "An Approach to the Social Aspects of Comprehensive Planning," and "Title I Project Proposal 1969-1970 And Two Subsequent Years."
    - Marcus Garvey Park Village Urban Renewal Plan, 1968 (Offsite-box 12, Folder 15)
    - McKinsey Report, 1969-1970 (Offsite-box 12, Folder 16)
    - Memoranda, 1967-1971 (Offsite-box 12, Folder 17)
    - Milbank-Frawley (3 Folders), 1966-1967 (Offsite-box 12, Folder 18-20)
    - Model Cities (2 Folders), 1967-1968 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 1-2)
    - Morningside Renewal (2 Folders), 1964-1965 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 3-4)
    - Morrisania (2 Folders), 1967-1970 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 5-6)
    - Mott Haven (3 Folders), 1967 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 7-9)
    - Multi Services (3 Folders), 1967-1970 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 10-12)
    - Newsletter (Dept of City Planning), 1967 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 13)
    - NYCHA Scatter Site VP [Vest Pocket], 1966-1972 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 14)
    - Open Space, 1968-1969 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 15)
    - Other Fed Agencies, 1968-1969 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 16)
    - Parks -- Open Space Beautification, 1966-1969 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 17)
    - Personnel, 1968-1969 (Offsite-box 14, Folder 1)
    - Physical Development, 1968 (Offsite-box 14, Folder 2)
      Contains plans for physical development and beautification programs in Central Brooklyn.
    - Physical Development (2 Folders), 1966-1969 (Offsite-box 14, Folder 3-4)
      Contents include: "Demolition Program," "Demolition Training," "Model Cities Vest Pocket Housing Progress Report (July 1968)," and "Neighborhood Development Program – Supplementary Fact Sheets."
    - Physical Development Task Forces (2 Folders), 1967-1969 (Offsite-box 14, Folder 5-6)
    - Planning (2 Folders), 1966-1982, bulk 1967-1969 (Offsite-box 14, Folder 7-8)
    - Policy Statement on Model Cities, 1969 (Offsite-box 14, Folder 9)
    - Policy Committee, 1968-1969 (Offsite-box 14, Folder 10)
    - Policy Committee (3 Folders), 1967-1972 (Offsite-box 14, Folder 11-13)
      Model Cities policy committee meeting agendas and notes.
    - Press, 1970 (Offsite-box 14, Folder 14)
    - Public Housing Sites, 1966-1967 (Offsite-box 14, Folder 15)
    - Public Works Forum, 1984 (Offsite-box 14, Folder 16)
    - Puerto Rican Organization for Urban Development, 1967 (Offsite-box 14, Folder 17)
    - Receivership (2 Folders), 1963-1967 (Offsite-box 14, Folder 18-19)
    - Resource Allocation (2 Folders), 1967-1968 (Offsite-box 14, Folder 20-21)
    - Retreats, 1968 (Offsite-box 14, Folder 22)
    - Rochdale Village, 1983 (Offsite-box 14, Folder 23)
    - Sanitation (2 Folders), 1967-1969 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 1-2)
    - Sanitation and Safety, 1968-1969 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 3)
    - Sanitation Task Force, 1968-1969 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 4)
    - South Bronx (3 Folders), 1968-1969 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 5-7)
    - South Bronx (3 Folders), 1967-1969 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 8-10)
    - Task Forces (2 Folders), 1968-1970 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 11-12)
      This file contains documentation related to the organization and implementation of the economic development, safety, physical development, health, sanitation, and multi-services task forces.
    - Twin Parks (4 Folders), 1966-1967 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 13-16)
    - UHF (United Housing Foundation) Publications, 1970 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 17)
    - Union Negotiation Demolition, 1968-1969 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 18)
    - UPACA (Upper Park Avenue Community Association), 1968-1972 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 19)
    - Urban Corps, 1967 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 20)
    - Urban Design, 1968, 1970 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 21)
    - Urban Renewal (2 Folders), 1966-1969 (Offsite-box 16, Folder 1-2)
    - Vest Pocket (8 Folders), 1966-1969 (Offsite-box 16, Folder 3-10)
      These files contain documentation related to the development and implementation of the Vest Pocket Housing program, which was the first step in New York's Model Cities program. It was designed to include community participation, neighborhood preservation, more housing with minimum uprooting, and a new emphasis on neighborhood design. The program took place in Mott Haven (South Bronx), Milbank-Frawley Circle (Harlem), Bedford-Stuyvesant (Central Brooklyn), and East New York.
    - Vest Pocket (5 Folders), 1966-1969 (Offsite-box 16, Folder 11-15)
    - Vest Pocket (3 Folders), 1967-1968 (Offsite-box 16, Folder 16-18)
    - Washington Heights Community Study, 1968 (Offsite-box 16, Folder 19)
    - Weeksville, 1968 (Offsite-box 16, Folder 20)
    - West Village Houses Preliminary Site Information, 1963-1964, 1968 (Offsite-box 16, Folder 21)
    - Woman's Hospital, 1964-1965 (Offsite-box 16, Folder 22)
- Series II. Housing and Urban Development, 1948-2011 (bulk 1970s-1980s)
  Series II consists of materials related to Flatow's work in housing and urban development, with a focus on mutual housing, infrastructure reliability, affordable housing, and equitable housing policy. The bulk of this material consists of correspondence, published reports, newsletters, and plans for various housing projects. As a consultant, Flatow worked on projects with several organizations, including the New York Urban Coalition's In Rem Housing Program and the Parodneck Foundation's 197a Plan for Bronx Community Board #3. There are also records from her work with the Consumer-Farmer Cooperative, the Regional Plan Association, and her role as Executive Deputy Secretary of State under New York Secretary of State Basil Paterson.
  - 83 Housing Bill, circa 1983-1984 (Offsite-box 16, Folder 23)
  - Affordable Housing, 1984-1986 (Offsite-box 16, Folder 24)
  - Annotated Playboy Interview with Edward Koch, circa 1980s (Offsite-box 16, Folder 25)
  - Arson, circa 1980 (Offsite-box 16, Folder 26)
  - Bronx Frontier (3 Folders), 1978-1985 (Offsite-box 17, Folder 1-3)
  - Charter Revision, 1983-1986 (Offsite-box 17, Folder 4)
  - Civic Affairs Forum, circa 1984-1985 (Offsite-box 17, Folder 5)
  - Coalition to House the Homeless, 1983-1984 (Offsite-box 17, Folder 6)
  - Columbia's Urban Design Program, circa 1977 (Offsite-box 17, Folder 7)
  - Community Assisted Tenant Controlled Housing (CATCH) Financial Assessment, 2011 (Offsite-box 17, Folder 8)
  - Community Board #3, Bronx, circa 1987-1989 (Offsite-box 17, Folder 9)
  - Community Boards, circa 1970-1985 (Offsite-box 17, Folder 10)
  - Community Development Credit Union (3 Folders), circa 1977-1984 (Offsite-box 17, Folder 11-13)
  - Coney Island (3 Folders of 4), circa 1966-1969 (Offsite-box 17, Folder 14-16)
  - Coney Island (1 Folder of 4). Oversize, circa 1966-1969 (Folder FF-1)
    File contains a 1968 Coney Island I Community Development/Land Use Plan by the City of New York Housing and Development Administration.
  - Consumer-Farmer Cooperator, 1973-1997 (Offsite-box 17, Folder 17)
    This file contains several issues of The Consumer-Farmer Cooperator, the annual publication of the Consumer-Farmer Foundation, Inc.
  - Consumer-Farmer Foundation Board (2 Folders), circa 1984-1998 (Offsite-box 17, Folder 18-19)
  - Cooper Square, circa 1984-1985 (Offsite-box 17, Folder 20)
  - Donald Elliott, circa 1978-1983 (Offsite-box 17, Folder 21)
  - The Future Metropolis, 1961 (Offsite-box 17, Folder 22)
  - Harlem, circa 1984-1985 (Offsite-box 17, Folder 23)
  - Housing Authority, 1973 (Offsite-box 17, Folder 24)
  - Housing History (4 Folders), circa 1948-1982 (Offsite-box 17, Folder 25-28)
  - Housing History, circa 1948-1982 (Offsite-box 18, Folder 1)
  - Housing Legislation, circa 1983 (Offsite-box 18, Folder 2)
  - Housing Policy (3 Folders), circa 1967-1985, bulk 1980-1982 (Offsite-box 18, Folder 3-5)
  - Housing Preservation and Development (HPD), circa 1983 (Offsite-box 18, Folder 6)
  - In Rem Housing Program (2 Folders), circa 1983-1985 (Offsite-box 18, Folder 7-8)
  - Infrastructure Reliability (4 Folders), 1977-1983 (Offsite-box 18, Folder 9-12)
  - The Leflagi Plan for Housing Now, 1971 December (Offsite-box 18, Folder 13)
  - Local Initiatives Support Corporation (LISC), 1980 (Offsite-box 18, Folder 14)
  - Low Income Housing Round-Up, 1984 (Offsite-box 18, Folder 15)
  - Memories of George Hervey Hallett, Jr., circa 1986 (Offsite-box 18, Folder 16)
  - Metropolis in The Making, 1955 (Offsite-box 18, Folder 17)
  - Model Cities (3 Folders), circa 1966-1993 (Offsite-box 18, Folder 18-20)
    This file contains materials related to plans for a survey and book about Model Cities. The idea was to trace people and ask for impressions, memories, anecdotes, and photos to tell the story of Model Cities as seen by its people.
  - Mortgage Rate Chart, undated (Offsite-box 18, Folder 21)
  - Mutual Housing (9 Folders), circa 1974-1991 (Offsite-box 18, Folder 22-30)
  - Neighborhoods, 1976-1984 (Offsite-box 19, Folder 1)
  - New York City Charter, 1977 (Offsite-box 19, Folder 2)
  - New York City Charter, 1985 (Offsite-box 19, Folder 3)
  - New York City Partnership, 1982-1983 (Offsite-box 19, Folder 4)
  - New York City: The Challenge Ahead (conference), circa 1989 (Offsite-box 19, Folder 5)
  - New York Urban Coalition (NYUC), circa 1970-1983 (Offsite-box 19, Folder 6)
  - New York Urban Coalition Housing Rehabilitation Task Force (report), 1976 January (Offsite-box 19, Folder 7)
  - NJ Housing, Mt Laurel (newspaper clippings), 1983-1985 (Offsite-box 19, Folder 8)
  - NYC Housing Authority (2 Folders), circa 1960s-2000s (Offsite-box 19, Folder 9-10)
  - New York City Housing Authority Data, 1982-1983 (Offsite-box 19, Folder 11)
  - NYC Labor Religion Coalition, 1985 (Offsite-box 19, Folder 12)
  - Open Space (2 Folders of 3), circa 1975-1980 (Offsite-box 19, Folder 13-14)
  - Open Space (1 Folder of 3). Oversize, circa 1975-1980 (Folder OS-Large, Folder 2)
    File contains a 1975 blueprint of parks and playgrounds in the Bronx.
  - Pan Urban Associates, Inc., 1985 (Offsite-box 19, Folder 15)
  - Pastoral and Educational Services, circa 1980s (Offsite-box 19, Folder 16)
  - Paterson Housing Authority (2 Folders), 1986-1992 (Offsite-box 19, Folder 17-18)
  - The Peoples Development Corporation (1 of 2), circa 1978-1979 (Offsite-box 19, Folder 19)
    The file contains materials related to The People's Development Corporation (PDC), a sweat-equity community housing group in the South Bronx. PDC undertook work in housing rehabilitation, tenant management, and energy conservation.
  - The Peoples Development Corporation (2 of 2). Oversize, circa 1978-1979 (Folder OS-Large, Folder 2)
    File contains a blueprint from the People's Development Corp. B.E.S.S Project.
  - Phipps Houses, 1983 (Offsite-box 19, Folder 20)
    This file contains a report titled "Proposal to Amend State and City Codes for Single Room Occupancy Housing."
  - Planning the Future of New York City (conference), 1979 (Offsite-box 19, Folder 21)
  - Population (3 Folders), circa 1979-1980 (Offsite-box 19, Folder 22-24)
  - A Proposal for Equitable Development in New York City (draft), 1983 December (Offsite-box 19, Folder 25)
  - Regional Plan Association, 1980-1985 (Offsite-box 19, Folder 26)
  - Rural Revitalization (2 Folders), 1979 (Offsite-box 19, Folder 27-28)
  - South Bronx Greenway (1 of 2), 1991-1994 (Offsite-box 20, Folder 1)
  - South Bronx Greenway (2 of 2). Oversize, 1991-1994 (Folder FF-1)
    File contains a blueprint of the community and service districts in the Bronx.
  - Special Crisis Intervention Program (3 Folders), circa 1980 (Offsite-box 20, Folder 2-4)
  - State Action Strategies, 1981 January (Offsite-box 20, Folder 5)
  - Statement on Housing and Action Plan, circa 1983-1985 (Offsite-box 20, Folder 6)
  - Strategies (2 Folders), 1978-1982 (Offsite-box 20, Folder 7-8)
  - Urban Resources Partnership, 1994-2000 (Offsite-box 20, Folder 9)
  - We're Still Here: The Rise, Fall, and Resurrection of the South Bronx, 1986 (Offsite-box 20, Folder 10)
- Series III. Waterfronts, Waterways, and Waterborne Transportation, 1943-2005 (bulk 1971-2005)
  Series III covers much of Eugenia Flatow's work concerning waterfront development and revitalization, the improvement of water quality and waterborne transportation, and the study of how environmental factors affect New York City's water supply. These materials primarily consist of correspondence, research files, surveys, reports, and published materials. For more information regarding Flatow's water-related work, see Series IV. Organizational Records.
  Series III is organized in four subseries:
  Subseries III.A. General Files, 1973-2000
  Subseries III.B. Water Quality, 1975-2005
  Subseries III.C. Combined Sewer Overflows, 1988-1999
  Subseries III.D. Published Materials, 1943-2001 (bulk 1971-1999)
  - Subseries III.A. General Files, 1973-2000
    Subseries III.A. includes files that chronicle Eugenia Flatow's water-related work. These materials primarily consist of research on waterborne transportation, reports on waterfront development and activity, and documents that detail how climate change and other environmental concerns affect water quality in New York City.
    - Beach Use and User Constraints in the New York City Coastal Region (report), 1979 (Offsite-box 20, Folder 11)
    - Bring Sailing Back, Inc., 1975-1977 (Offsite-box 20, Folder 12)
    - Climate Change, circa 1980s-1990s (Offsite-box 20, Folder 13)
    - Coastal Nonpoint Program (report), circa 1991 (Offsite-box 20, Folder 14)
    - Demonstration of a Coordinative Mechanism for Waterfront-related Planning (draft), 1977 (Offsite-box 20, Folder 15)
    - Design for Boating, undated (Offsite-box 20, Folder 16)
    - The East River Tidal Barrage (preprint), 1993 (Offsite-box 20, Folder 17)
    - Energy, 1978-1984 (Offsite-box 20, Folder 18)
    - An Evaluation of New York State's Tidal Wetlands Program (report), 1987 (Offsite-box 20, Folder 19)
    - Harlem River, 1987-1994 (Offsite-box 20, Folder 20)
    - Homeport, 1984-1985 (Offsite-box 20, Folder 21)
    - Hudson River, 1989-1993 (Offsite-box 20, Folder 22)
    - Marine Environments, circa 1989 (Offsite-box 20, Folder 23)
    - Minimizing Risks and Sharing Liability from Application of Sludge and Sludge By-Products on Agricultural Land (report), 1993 (Offsite-box 20, Folder 24)
    - National Maritime Historical Society, 1982-1986 (Offsite-box 20, Folder 25)
    - Native Species Planting Guide for New York City and Vicinity, 1993 (Offsite-box 21, Folder 1)
    - Natural Areas Refuges, 1988 (Offsite-box 21, Folder 2)
    - The New York City Water and Sewer System (financial report), 1997 (Offsite-box 21, Folder 3)
    - New York State Maritime Museum, 1973 (Offsite-box 21, Folder 4)
    - Nitrogen, circa 1990s (Offsite-box 21, Folder 5)
    - North River, 1991-1993 (Offsite-box 21, Folder 6)
    - Notebooks, circa 1985 (Offsite-box 21, Folder 7)
    - Pesticides Research Strategy (draft), 1983 (Offsite-box 21, Folder 8)
    - Pilot Schooner, circa 1985 (Offsite-box 21, Folder 9)
    - Port Authority Fishport, 1985 (Offsite-box 21, Folder 10)
    - A Proposal for the Development of a Low-cost Riverfront Swimming Pool Prototype, circa 1976 (Offsite-box 21, Folder 11)
    - Pursuing Beneficial Uses of Sludge (conference), 1992 (Offsite-box 21, Folder 12)
    - Queens, 1974-1985 (Offsite-box 21, Folder 13)
    - Safeguarding the Kensico: A Low-Impact Alternative Plan, 2000 (Offsite-box 21, Folder 14)
    - Shore Walkers, 1984 (Offsite-box 21, Folder 15)
    - Staten Island (2 Folders), 1975-1985 (Offsite-box 21, Folder 16-17)
    - Still at Risk (report), circa 1995 (Offsite-box 21, Folder 18)
      Report on the Oversight Hearing Held by the Assembly Legislative Task Force on Long Island Sound on the Oil Spill Prevention and Contingency Act of 1990.
    - Task 524.01, undated (Offsite-box 21, Folder 19)
      Task 524.01 required the screening of waterfront activities, as related to water quality objectives. This report documents changes along waterfront areas, projected developments, and the change or impact resulting from those developments.
    - Transportation Access, 1975-1984 (Offsite-box 21, Folder 20)
    - Tributary Studies, 1978 (Offsite-box 21, Folder 21)
    - Water Authority, 1979-1982 (Offsite-box 21, Folder 22)
    - Water Resources Institute, 1979-1984 (Offsite-box 21, Folder 23)
    - Waterfront Revitalization (2 Folders), 1980-1985 (Offsite-box 21, Folder 24-25)
    - Weatherization (2 Folders), circa 1980s (Offsite-box 21, Folder 26-27)
    - World Famous Sailing Ships (prints), 1986 (Offsite-box 21, Folder 28)
  - Subseries III.B. Water Quality, 1975-2005
    Subseries III.B. consists of surveys and reports concerning the water quality of the New York Harbor. There are also materials related to Section 208 of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act, the bulk of which document the activities of the Citizens Advisory Committee (CAC). The NYC Department of Water Resources and the Department of City Planning formed CAC to carry out the statutory requirement for public participation in water quality planning.
    - Section 208 (2 Folders), 1975-1980 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 1-2)
    - New Jersey Alliance for Action, 1983-1985 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 3)
    - New York Harbor Water Quality Survey, 1984 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 4)
    - A Summary of Water Quality Data for the Summers of 1984 and 1985, 1986 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 5)
    - Gateway National Recreation Area, Bacteriological Water Quality Five Year Trend Analysis 1984-1988, 1989 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 6)
    - Thirsty City: A Plan of Action for New York City Water Supply, 1986 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 7)
    - Water-Watchers: A Citizens Guide to New York City Water Supply, 1987 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 8)
    - Conference on the Impacts of New York Harbor Development on Aquatic Resources, 1987 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 9)
    - Water for a Thirsty City, 1992 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 10)
    - The State of The City's Waters, 1994 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 11)
    - CAPA Regulations, 1994 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 12)
    - New York Harbor Water Quality Survey Executive Summary, 1994 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 13)
    - New York Harbor Water Quality Survey, 1994 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 14)
    - New York Harbor Water Quality Survey Appendices, 1994 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 15)
    - New York Harbor Water Quality Survey Executive Summary, 1998 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 16)
    - New York Harbor Water Quality Regional Report, 1998 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 17)
    - 2001 New York Harbor Water Quality Report (Offsite-box 22, Folder 18)
    - 2003 New York Harbor Water Quality Report (Offsite-box 22, Folder 19)
    - 2005 New York Harbor Water Quality Report (Offsite-box 22, Folder 20)
  - Subseries III.C. Combined Sewer Overflows, 1988-1999
    Subseries III.C. includes correspondence, meeting minutes, progress summaries, and drafts of reports related to the management of Combined Sewer Overflows (CSOs). Many of these records document the activities of the New York Department of Environmental Protection's (DEP) Citizens Advisory Committee (CAC), which was part of a citywide effort to abate CSOs in the East River, Inner Harbor, Outer Harbor, and Jamaica Bay.
    - Jamaica Bay (2 Folders), 1989-1992 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 21-22)
    - East River (3 Folders), 1988-1994 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 23-25)
    - Inner Harbor (3 Folders), 1989-1993 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 26-28)
    - Outer Harbor (2 Folders), 1990-1992 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 29-30)
    - CSO's (2 Folders), 1988-1999 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 1-2)
    - CSO 95/96 (2 Folders), 1995-1996 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 3-4)
    - CSO 1997 (3 Folders) (Offsite-box 23, Folder 5-7)
    - CSO Programs, 1985-1995 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 8)
  - Subseries III.D. Published Materials, 1943-2001 (bulk 1971-1999)
    Subseries III.D. contains printed matter related to waterborne transportation and the development of the New Jersey and New York waterfronts. The bulk of the material consists of reports and brochures published by agencies such as the New York City Department of Ports and Terminals, the Port Authority of NY & NJ, the New York City Department of Environmental Protection, and the New York City Department of City Planning.
    Materials in this series are arranged chronologically.
    - Roots in the Earth, 1943 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 9)
    - The Lower Hudson, 1966 December (Offsite-box 23, Folder 10)
    - The Year of the Whale, 1969 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 11)
    - The Waterfront: Supplement to Plan For New York City, 1971 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 12)
    - The New York City Waterfront: A Comprehensive Planning Workshop, 1974 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 13)
    - The New York City Waterfront: A Multimedia Interdisciplinary Discovery Approach (3 Folders), 1974 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 14-16)
    - Crossing the Sound: A Study of Improved Ferry Service on Long Island Sound, 1975 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 17)
    - Liberty Park, circa 1976 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 18)
    - Ship Souvenir Programs, circa 1976 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 19)
    - Reviving the Urban Waterfront, circa 1977 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 20)
    - The Second Wave and Other Tales, circa 1977-1978 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 21)
    - Oxygen Depletion and Associated Benthic Mortalities in New York Bight, 1976, 1979 December (Offsite-box 23, Folder 22)
    - Issues and Options in Regional Water Supply, 1979 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 23)
    - Please Go Near the Water: A Marine Field Trip Manual, 1980 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 24)
    - On the Waterfront and Other Tales of New York Industry, 1980 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 1)
    - Waterfront Revitalization: New York City Waterfront Revitalization Program (2 Folders), 1982 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 2-3)
    - What's Happening on the Waterfront, 1983 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 4)
    - Legal Foundations of Environmental Planning, 1983 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 5)
    - Brooklyn Reports, circa 1983-1984 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 6)
    - Neptune's Revenge: The Ocean of Tomorrow, 1984 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 7)
    - From Holystones to Gantry Cranes: A Brief History of the Seamen's Church Institute of New York and New Jersey, circa 1984-1985 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 8)
    - Saving Water from the Ground Up, 1985 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 9)
    - New Jersey: The Maritime State, circa 1985 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 10)
    - America's Coasts: Progress and Promise, circa 1985 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 11)
    - Neighborhood: The Journal for City Preservation, 1985 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 12)